# MIGUELMARCO RAMCHARAN

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

- **\** 061 149 8474
- Q Durban, South Africa
- www.codebymarco.com

## SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React
- Node.js
- ExpressJS
- Golang
- SQL / NoSQL
- PostgreSQL
- Jenkins
- RabbitMO
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- AWS / GCP

## **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2016 RYDALPARK SECONDARY

• High school diploma

## HOBBIES

- Football
- Watching Netflix
- Coding
- Watching history documentaries
- Learning about space

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I'm a 25 year old self-taught developer, which means I don't have a formal degree and I am getting old. After finishing high school, I started working for my dad—I had worked for him before, but that was more like child labor. In 2021, I began watching coding tutorials on YouTube. Before I knew it, I went from creating UIs using HTML and CSS to building APIs and getting hired. Now, I'm approaching two years in the tech industry, and I can't wait to see what the future holds for me.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **El Shaddai Interiors**

2017 - 2022

Carpenter

I started working for my dad after finishing high school, where we specialized in making custom cabinets and kitchen cupboards.

#### Responsibilities:

- Checked the quality of materials before use.
- · Performed daily inventory checks.
- · Assembled cabinets using high-quality materials.
- Applied finishing touches to cabinets before presenting them to clients.
- · Created cutting lists needed for each cabinet.

#### Decidio

2023 - PRESENT

Software Developer

This was my first tech job.

### Responsibilities:

- Initially provided support for the Truendo product.
- · Identified and fixed bugs.
- Implemented new features.
- Assisted in developer operations.
- Created standard operating procedures.

### Key Achievements:

- Developed consent record upload functionality, transferring data from a PostgreSQL database to Amazon S3.
- Implemented a geo feature to serve different scripts and configurations based on activated geographic regions.
- · Created various general-purpose APIs.